♪ In the face of turmoil ♪
♪ 面对混乱 ♪
♪ Its roots hold firmly ♪
♪ 它的根牢牢地扎根 ♪
♪ To this piece of land ♪
♪ 来到这片土地 ♪
♪ Searching for the waves ♪
♪ 寻找海浪 ♪
♪ My leaves flutter ♪
♪ 我的叶子飘动 ♪
♪ The horizon ♪
♪ 地平线 ♪
♪ Dealing from afar ♪
♪ 远方交易 ♪
♪ At the end of the world ♪
♪ 在世界的尽头 ♪
♪ It's eternity ♪
♪ 这是永恒 ♪
♪ When we meet and then part ♪
♪ 当我们相遇然后分离 ♪
♪ When we depend on each other and then move away ♪
♪ 当我们互相依赖 然后离开时 ♪
♪ I never forgot it ♪
♪ 我从未忘记 ♪
♪ By cutting the shine of swords ♪
♪ 削减剑的光芒 ♪
♪ Through the dappled sky ♪
♪ 穿过斑驳的天空 ♪
♪ Dreams that fall ♪
♪ 坠落的梦想 ♪
♪ Shatter in the wind ♪
♪ 随风破碎 ♪
♪ As the wind cuts through the waves ♪
♪ 风破浪而过 ♪
♪ Watch thousands of candles cross ♪
♪ 观看数千支蜡烛交叉 ♪
♪ The vast land and the boundless sea ♪
♪ 辽阔的土地和无边的海洋 ♪
♪ Armor and red robes flying high ♪
♪ 铠甲和红袍高飞 ♪
♪ Against bitterness, intense emotions and joyful adventures ♪
♪ 对抗苦涩、 强烈的情绪和快乐的冒险 ♪
♪ I just wish you were by my side ♪
♪ 我只希望你在我身边 ♪
♪ Make the most of what life has to offer ♪
♪ 充分利用生活所提供的一切 ♪
♪ Like tall trees with interconnected roots, I will accompany you to the ends ♪
♪ 就像根相连的大树一样 ，我会陪你走到尽头 ♪
♪ Watching the fireflies land on our shoulders ♪
♪ 看着萤火虫落在 我们的肩上 ♪
♪ Don't regret it, there are no doubts in this world ♪
♪ 不要后悔，这世界上没有疑虑 ♪
= Wonders of love =
=爱的奇迹=
= Episode 18 =
= 第 18 集 =
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Please.
请。
Shu.
舒。
Young Master!
少爷！
Young Master, you are awake.
少爷，您醒了。
Young master, you are finally awake.
少爷，您终于醒了。
Where is the lieutenant?
中尉在哪里？
Lieutenant is fine.
中尉很好。
Lieutenant is really fine.
中尉确实不错。
I SAW the Zhenxi army rushing across the top of the mountain.
只见镇西军 冲过山顶。
I'm sure they saved her.
我确信他们救了她。
Young Master, you need rest and recovery.
少爷，您需要 休息，恢复体力。
We still have to see Lieutenant He when we get back.
回来后还要去见何中尉。
Here.
这里。
(Which)
（哪个）
(Zhenxi)
(Zhenxi)
General.
一般的。
Great General.
伟大的将军。
I'm glad you're back.
我很高兴你回来了。
Mr. Qin,
Mr. Qin,
I have told my men to send Lord Xin and Lord Qi back to your camp.
我已经吩咐人送 辛公和齐公回营了。
As for your father,
至于你的父亲，
since you are already here,
既然你已经在这里了，
you can pick it up later.
你可以稍后再取。
Great General Cui, you have a kind heart.
伟大的崔将军，您有 一颗善良的心。
I am eternally grateful to you.
我永远感激你。
Mr. Qin,
Mr. Qin,
since you are already in my camp,
既然你已经在我的营地里了
Why don't we talk privately inside the tent?
我们为什么不在 帐篷里私下谈谈呢？
Clear.
清除。
I was planning to do it too.
我也打算这么做。
Finally we return.
最后我们回来了。
You have finally seen the Great General again.
你终于又见到大将军了。
My father has become thinner.
我的父亲变瘦了。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I looked at the Great General's face right now.
我现在看着大将军的脸。
I'm sure it's as healthy as ever.
我确信它和以前一样健康。
Lieutenant, don't worry about him.
中尉，别担心他。
Lieutenant,
中尉，
Aren't you worried at all?
你一点都不担心吗？
Worried about what?
担心什么？
This is the Cui Army camp.
这里是崔军营。
Li Ni doesn't dare to do anything with Father.
李妮不敢对 父亲做什么。
That's not what I mean.
我不是这个意思。
From
从
you're not worried
你不担心
Great General could you do something about Lord Qin?
大将军能帮 一下秦大人吗？
Ves,
维斯，
Great General could have set up an ambush
大将军可能会 设下埋伏
before inviting Lord Qin into his tent.
才请秦大人进帐。
Once you're inside,
一旦你进去了，
will give the order to kill
将下令杀人
crushing the cup.
压碎杯子。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
That will not happen.
那不会发生。
Lieutenant,
中尉，
you trust Lord Qin
你信任秦王
or the Great General both
或大将军两者
so you can be so sure about it?
所以你就可以这么肯定吗？
I trust none of them.
我不相信他们中的任何一个。
That pin,
那个别针，
Mr. Qin, why do you have it with you?
秦先生，你怎么带着它？
Miss Cui gave it to me.
崔小姐给我的。
Mr. Qin,
Mr. Qin,
do you think that
你认为
can you act brazen about it?
你能厚颜无耻吗？
Great General Cui, you misunderstood me.
崔大将军，您误会了。
I escorted Miss Cui back here today
今天我护送崔小姐回来了
because I have
因为我有
urgent matters to discuss with you.
有紧急事情要和你商量。
Mr. Qin, you wish to borrow the strength of the Cui army
秦先生，你想借用 崔军的力量
to claim Xichang, right?
声称西昌是吧？
Mr. Qin, you blackmailed me
秦先生，你敲诈我了
with your letter previous to this one.
与您在这封信之前的信一起。
Today, he even accompanied my daughter back.
今天他还 陪我女儿回来了。
Mr. Qin, I assume that
秦先生，我想
you think I don't dare
你以为我不敢
decapitarte, ¿eh?
斩首，呃？
However,
然而，
I trust both at the same time.
我同时信任两者。
What kind of enigma was that?
那是怎样的一个谜呢？
I don't understand at all.
我完全不明白。
Why are you so anxious?
你为什么这么着急？
I almost forgot.
我差点忘了。
Is Xie Chang'er here too?
谢嫦儿也来了？
Are you worried that
你是否担心
the great General could kill Lord Qin
大将军可以杀秦王
and his followers too, right?
还有他的追随者，对吗？
Lieutenant,
中尉，
I'm seriously.
我是认真的。
You always bother me.
你总是打扰我。
Great General!
伟大的将军！
¡Padre!
¡神父！
It's time to eat.
吃饭的时间到了。
Try the noodles I made for you.
尝尝我给你做的面条。
It's delicious.
这很美味。
Yeah,
是的，
why didn't you ask me
你为什么不问我
Where has Lord Qin gone?
秦王去哪儿了？
Father, don't tell me
父亲，别告诉我
Do you want to kill Lord Qin?
你想杀秦王吗？
He arrested my daughter
他逮捕了我女儿
and he blackmailed me with his letter.
他用信勒索我。
Shouldn't I kill him then?
那我不应该杀了他吗？
Padre,
神父，
you arrested your two brothers
你逮捕了你的两个兄弟
and also his father.
还有他的父亲。
This is why Lord Qin has no choice.
这也是秦王别无选择的原因。
but walk me back without fighting.
但不要打架，送我回去 。
Even now.
即使是现在。
Now that I think about it,
现在我想起来了，
you get a better deal.
你会得到更好的交易。
I wanted to ask you this.
我想问你这个。
Why did you give Lord Qin the hair pin to your mother ?
秦王爷为何把 簪子送给你母亲？
I leave you?
我离开你？
It's because he won a bet.
因为他打赌赢了。
That was my reward for him.
这就是我对他的奖励。
What kind of bet?
什么样的赌注？
What kind of bet is so valuable
什么样的赌注如此有价值
that you are using the sakeepsake your mother left you as a reward?
你正在用 你母亲留给你的清酒作为奖励？
Father, it is so.
父亲，原来如此。
Back then, when we were in Bingzhou,
当年，我们在并州的时候，
Han Li fell with us.
韩立也跟着我们一起倒下了。
Both Li Ni and I
我和李妮
They were in danger.
他们处于危险之中。
Therefore,
所以，
We made a bet.
我们打赌。
The winner of the bet
赌注的赢家
you will receive the other person's help to escape
你会得到对方的帮助 来逃脱
the place successfully.
成功的地方。
The loser will stay in Bingzhou as backup.
失败者将留在并州 作为后备。
Li Ni lost the bet.
李妮赌输了。
Therefore,
所以，
He helped me escape first.
他先帮我逃了出来。
My dear ones
我亲爱的人们
As a reward.
作为奖励。
Without sense.
毫无意义。
You won the bet, right?
你赌赢了，对吧？
Why did you give him a reward?
你为什么给他奖励？
Could be
可能
that he lost you on purpose?
他是故意失去你的吗？
Padre.
神父。
Yeah,
是的，
Do not let that fool you.
不要让它欺骗你。
Why would I let you know
我为什么要让你知道
if you lost it on purpose
如果你故意丢失它
so you can escape safely?
这样你就可以安全逃脱了？
Padre,
神父，
do you think your daughter is so stupid?
你以为你女儿这么傻吗？
It's hard to say.
很难说。
Maybe she went crazy suddenly.
也许她突然疯了 。
Anyway,
反正，
this chest fooled my daughter
这个胸部欺骗了我的女儿
and even trapped her in Taiqing Palace.
甚至将她困在太清宫。
It's despicable.
这是卑鄙的。
It's true.
这是真的。
Li Ni
李妮
It's finally in my hands now.
现在终于到了我的手里了。
I will kill him
我会杀他
to vent.
发泄。
Now, Dongdu is under the control of the Cui Army.
现在，东都已在 崔军的控制之下。
Once we claim Xichang,
一旦我们占领了西昌，
Peace will be restored to the world.
世界将恢复和平。
The wish you made when you left Yingzhou,
你离开瀛州时许下的心愿，
what was for the people
什么是为了人民
lead a peaceful life,
过着平静的生活，
It will soon be done.
很快就会完成。
Padre,
神父，
If you kill Li Ni right now,
如果你现在杀了李妮
people will not be able
人们将无法
live in peace.
安居乐业。
You didn't say that
你没这么说
when they were in Yingzhou.
当他们在瀛州的时候。
You said that the imperial Li Family was incompetent.
你说李家皇族 无能。
Only those who were capable should rule the world.
只有有能力的人 才能统治世界。
At that time,
当时，
He still didn't know Li Ni.
他还不认识李妮。
Padre,
神父，
listen.
听。
Li Ni.
李妮.
Comes from Laolan Pass.
来自老兰关。
Excels in battles.
在战斗中表现出色。
The strangest thing about him
他最奇怪的一点是
It's not utilitarian.
这不是功利主义的。
He just wants to quell the rebellion
他只是想平息叛乱
and return to his step.
然后回到他的脚步。
He is someone who can bear great responsibilities
他是一个能够承担 重大责任的人
with a benevolent heart.
怀着一颗仁慈的心。
A person like him
像他这样的人
he is the best ruler
他是最好的统治者
after the ravages of war.
经过战争的破坏。
But,
但，
the world will fall into chaos again
世界将再次陷入混乱
It doesn't matter who ascended the throne.
谁登上王位并不重要。
You have always been a proud person.
你一直是一个骄傲的人。
I never thought that you
我从没想过你
Li Ni would like it so much.
李妮非常喜欢。
I have already killed him.
我已经杀了他了。
Don't mention it again.
别再提了。
I do not trust you.
我不相信你。
Father, you will never kill him.
父亲，您永远不会杀他。
Because you said so?
因为你这么说？
It's because I know you well.
那是因为我很了解你。
No matter how much you hate it,
不管你多么讨厌它，
you have to wait until we claim Xichang
你必须等到 我们占领西昌
before you burn your bridges
在你自毁前程之前
and kill him.
并杀了他。
So according to you,
所以根据你的说法，
we should keep lord qin alive
我们要保住秦王的性命
as it is still useful to us.
因为它对我们仍然有用。
Clear.
清除。
Padre.
神父。
Hurry up.
赶快。
My daughter told me
我女儿告诉我
you are still useful to us.
你对我们还是有用的。
For now I won't kill you.
现在我不会杀你。
You're stupid?
你好蠢？
You must flee if you cannot defeat my father.
如果你不能打败我父亲，你就必须逃走。
Do you like it when he ties you up
你喜欢他把你绑起来吗
and put you in a box?
然后把你放进盒子里？
It's not that I can't defeat him.
并不是说我不能打败他。
I mean, I can't defeat him.
我的意思是，我无法打败他。
Still, I can't just escape.
尽管如此，我还是不能逃避。
I had hope
我曾有希望
that the Great General Cui
那个崔大将军
can help the Zhenxi army
可以帮助镇西军
reclamar Xichang.
reclamar Xichang.
So, father, you promised Lord Qin
所以，父亲，您答应了秦大人
to claim Xichang with him?
与他一起占领 西昌？
Thanks, Dad!
感谢爸爸！
Now, you don't have to worry.
现在，您不必担心。
You don't need to encourage me to eat.
你不需要鼓励我吃饭。
Your noodles must have been worn out by now.
你的面条现在肯定已经吃完了。
I'll make you another dish right away!
我马上再给你做一道菜！
Slows down.
慢下来。
Take your time.
慢慢来。
Alright?
好吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Did the rope do this to you?
绳子对你做了这样的事吗？
Alright. I'll be fine after a few days.
好吧。 几天后我就会好的。
You're so stupid.
你太蠢了。
A small punishment is fine, but you should run away when it is serious.
轻微的惩罚还好， 严重的就逃走。
You are an adult.
你是一个成年人了。
You were tied and trapped in the box for an unknown amount of time.
你被绑在箱子里，被困了 不知多久。
Aren't you afraid that you might get hurt?
你就不怕 自己受伤吗？
It wasn't that long.
时间并没有那么长。
Ves,
维斯，
before entering,
进入之前，
great General said
伟大的将军说
Could you send your troops and help me claim
你能派你的部队 来帮我夺取领土吗
xichang,
西昌,
However, you have to tie me down
然而你却必须束缚我
and keep me in a box.
并将我放在一个盒子里。
Everything depended on your will.
一切都取决于你的意愿。
If you want to die,
如果你想死的话
He wouldn't need to send his troops.
他不需要派出军队。
He would cut off my head immediately.
他会立即砍下我的头。
However, if you want
但是，如果你想要
to keep me alive,
让我活下去，
He promised me that he would send his troops and helped me reclaim Xichang.
他答应我，他会派兵 帮助我收复西昌。
are you so sure
你这么确定吗
that he didn't want you dead?
他不想让你死？
What if I tricked you into escorting me?
如果我骗你陪我怎么办？
to the main camp of the Cui Army
至崔军主营
so I could seek my revenge?
这样我就可以报仇了？
Trapped me in Taiqing Palace
把我困在太清宫
for a long time after all.
毕竟很长一段时间了。
Are you mad at me?
你气死我了？
Clear.
清除。
Did you really hold a grudge?
你真的有记仇吗？
Naturally.
自然。
If so, it would not be enough
如果是这样，那还不够
if you just asked your father
如果你问你父亲
cut off my head
砍下我的头
I have an idea.
我有个主意。
What idea?
什么想法？
Ya ves,
是的，
a life is a long time.
一生是一段很长的时间。
From now on, why don't you torture me
从今往后，你何不折磨我
and organize myself around
并组织自己围绕
every day?
每天？
You can free me from your frustrations
你可以让我摆脱你的挫败感
every time you feel it.
每次你感觉到的时候。
I think that
我觉得
is more suitable.
更合适。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
You just want.
你只是想要。
I wish for that to happen.
我希望这一切能够发生。
What should I do?
我应该怎么办？
What should I say?
我应该说什么？
¿ Taozi?
¿ Taozi?
Eat it.
吃了它。
What's the matter?
怎么了？
you were walking around
你正在四处走动
like a cat on a hot tin roof.
就像一只热铁皮屋顶上的猫。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I have already consulted Lord Qin.
我已经请教过秦大人了。
You're safe.
你安全了。
is eating together
正在一起吃饭
lieutenant He in his tent now.
何中尉现在在他的帐篷里。
Actually,
实际上，
actually, it was not because of Lord Qin.
其实，并不是因为秦王。
Wasn't it because of Lord Qin?
还不是因为秦王爷吗？
What happens then?
然后会发生什么？
Yo...
哟...
I was afraid
我害怕
I was afraid of not being able to see you again.
我害怕再也见不到 你了。
You want to see me every day, huh?
你每天都想见我，是吗？
However,
然而，
We will part soon.
我们很快就会分开。
And, a war comes.
而且，战争来临了。
What happens if I get hurt?
如果我受伤怎么办？
o...
哦...
No one will tell you anyway.
反正没人会告诉你。
it's possible
这是可能的
I won't see you again after this.
从此以后我不会再见到你了。
What nonsense are you talking?
你在胡说什么？
You will not be injured.
你不会受伤。
You didn't listen to nonsense.
你没听废话。
You're right.
你说得对。
I have the medicine you gave me.
你给我的药我有。
It's okay even if I get injured.
就算我受伤了也没关系。
What a stupid guy.
真是个愚蠢的家伙。
Eat it. It's getting cold.
吃了它。天越来越冷了。
You need to be careful
你需要小心
when you fight in war.
当你在战争中作战时。
Don't think that you are going to get injured.
不要以为 你会受伤。
He is so cute!
他是如此可爱！
Slows down.
慢下来。
The doctor said that
医生说
I must not let yourself exaggerate.
我决不能让自己夸大其词。
I do not know
我不知道
whether Ying is safe or not.
莹是否安全。
How can I wait?
我怎么能等呢？
However, you have not fully recovered yet.
然而，你还没有 完全康复。
You're hurting yourself by running like that.
你 这样跑步是在伤害自己。
Look at the markings on the road.
看看路上的标记。
Cui's army is nearby.
崔军就在附近。
I have to go back to camp today.
我今天必须回营地。
I can only rest easy when I see Ying.
见到莹我才安心。
Young master,
少爷，
Lieutenant He is blessed by the heavens.
中尉他是有上天眷顾的。
I'm sure it's fine.
我确信没问题。
Young Master!
少爷！
Shu, date prisa.
舒，枣prisa。
Yeah,
是的，
I can't bear to part with you.
我不忍心与你分开。
Why don't you stay then?
那你为什么不留下来呢？
Wanna
想
to bring you with me.
带你跟我一起。
But I fear that Great General Cui
但我怕崔大将军
won't accept it.
不会接受的。
You and your desires.
你和你的愿望。
I have a gift for you.
我有一个礼物送你。
young master,
少爷，
We have arrived at the camp.
我们已经到达营地了。
What...
什么...
Isn't that a lieutenant?
这不是中尉吗？
Yeah.
是的。
can keep you company
可以陪伴你
as long as he's not around.
只要他不在身边。
You can hit it,
可以打啊
smash it, or throw it around
打碎它，或者把它扔得到处都是
when you're upset.
当你心烦意乱的时候。
This straw figure
这个稻草人像
looks like you.
看起来像你。
If you like,
如果你喜欢，
I will make other types for you next time.
下次我会为你做其他类型的。
If so, you should
如果是这样，你应该
make another one next time.
下次再做一份。
If not, I would be alone
如果没有的话我就孤身一人了
with no friends.
没有朋友。
Young teacher.
年轻的老师。
It's getting late.
天色已晚。
You should go now.
你现在应该走了。
Yeah!
是的！
♪ Between the moonlight, your vows ♪
♪ 月光下，你的誓言 ♪
And.
和。
Once peace restored to the world,
一旦 世界恢复和平，
I will definitely marry you.
我一定会嫁给你的。
♪ Tell me about you forever ♪
♪ 告诉我关于你的永远 ♪
Wait for my proposal!
等我的提议！
I will definitely go ask you about your hands.
我一定会去 问问你的手的情况。
♪ It's still you ♪
♪ 依然是你 ♪
♪ What can make me ignore everything ♪
♪ 什么能让我忽略一切 ♪
I want to marry you.
我想和你结婚。
I want to marry you!
我想和你结婚！
♪ We search together ♪
♪ 我们一起寻找 ♪
Yay!
耶！
I want to marry you!
我想和你结婚！
♪ carrying the broken world ♪
♪ 承载着破碎的世界 ♪
♪ you give me a firm belief ♪
♪ 你给了我坚定的信念 ♪
♪ In adversity, the only light is the love that never dies ♪
♪ 逆境中 唯一的光明就是不灭的爱 ♪
♪ Every separation I've ever endured ♪
♪ 我所经历的每一次分离 ♪
♪ Every second I look for you in the night ♪
♪ 夜里我每一秒都在寻找你 ♪
♪ Without fear of the obstacles that hurt me, I want to love until the end ♪
♪ 不惧怕伤害我的障碍， 我想爱到底 ♪
Young Master!
少爷！
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Let's leave this place.
我们离开这个地方吧。
♪ Twist the night, venture through adversity ♪
♪ 扭转黑夜， 穿越逆境 ♪
♪ making the heart burn with passion ♪
♪ 激情燃烧 ♪
♪ You are by my side ♪
♪ 你在我身边 ♪
Mr. Qin,
Mr. Qin,
It's time for you to go.
你该走了。
♪ hastening towards our eternal vow ♪
♪ 奔赴我们永恒的誓言 ♪
Yeah,
是的，
be careful.
当心。
Wait for me.
等我。
♪ Aiming at the destination, with persistence ♪
♪ 瞄准目的地， 坚持不懈 ♪
♪ And not letting go, next to you ♪
♪ 不放手， 在你身边 ♪
♪ In resentment, completing our world ♪
♪ 在怨恨中， 完成我们的世界 ♪
♪ The eternal custody of this lasting love ♪
♪ 这份永恒的爱的永恒守护 ♪
♪ Enter into the belief you gave me ♪
♪ 进入你给我的信念 ♪
♪ Without fear of the obstacles that hurt us, we are until the end ♪
♪ 不惧怕伤害我们的障碍， 我们会一直走到最后 ♪
♪ Break the night with you ♪
♪ 与你共度夜晚 ♪
♪ Keeping our belief ♪
♪ 坚守我们的信念 ♪
♪ holding your hand until the end of time ♪
♪ 牵着你的手 直到时间的尽头 ♪
♪ The eternal custody of this lasting love ♪
♪ 这份永恒的爱的永恒守护 ♪
♪ We've all made it through the night ♪
♪ 我们都熬过了这个夜晚 ♪
♪ Without fear of the obstacles that hurt us, we are until the end ♪
♪ 不惧怕伤害我们的障碍， 我们会一直走到最后 ♪
♪ unalterable ♪
♪ 不可改变 ♪
(Yeah,)
（是的，）
(Once peace restored to the world,)
（一旦 世界恢复和平，）
I will definitely marry you.
我一定会嫁给你的。
I want to marry you!
我想和你结婚！
Young master,
少爷，
let's go back.
我们回去吧。
Where?
在哪里？
I don't have a house anymore.
我已经没有房子了。
But...
但...
We have nowhere else to go back to
我们无处可去
If we don't return to the Cui Army.
如果不回崔军。
There is no place for me.
没有我的位置。
There is no path I can follow.
我无路可走。
There is no medicine that can cure me.
没有药物 可以治愈我。
♪ Reminding about that first moment ♪
♪ 回忆起最初的时刻 ♪
Who I am?
我是谁？
I'm not Cui Lin.
我不是崔琳。
♪ Wait for my inner scars to heal ♪
♪ 等待我内心的伤疤痊愈 ♪
Had been born
已经诞生了
without a name.
没有名字。
I lived like Cui Lin
我像崔琳一样生活
for so many years.
这么多年了。
I already forgot
我已经忘记了
who was.
谁是。
For your own good.
为了你好。
For Ying's sake.
为了莹的缘故。
♪ I still remember our past ♪
♪ 我还记得我们的过去 ♪
But now,
但现在，
He doesn't need me anymore.
他不再需要我了。
I have already become
我已经成为
in his shadow
在他的影子下
But now,
但现在，
no longer need
不再需要
needs a shadow like me.
需要像我这样的影子。
I have no idea
我不知道
How am I supposed to keep living!
我该怎么继续活下去！
Young master!
少爷！
♪ If only I could appreciate this momentary warmth ♪
♪ 如果我能体会 这短暂的温暖就好了 ♪
♪ If only I could live this moment for you ♪
♪ 如果我能 为你活这一刻就好了 ♪
♪ My memory sinks, and my heart breaks ♪
♪ 我的记忆沉沦，我的心碎了 ♪
Shu,
舒，
♪ Life and death mean nothing ♪
♪ 生与死毫无意义 ♪
I always thought that
我一直以为
It wasn't Cui Lin.
不是崔琳。
She is the real Cui Lin.
她才是真正的崔琳。
Even if it's a girl,
就算是个女孩子，
Both Father
两人都是父亲
y Ying
y英
I no longer need a shadow like me.
我不再需要像我一样的影子。
A shadow that was abandoned by its master.
被主人抛弃的影子。
Useless shadow.
无用的影子。
It is impossible
是不可能的
now between Ying and me.
现在是我和莹之间。
All my fault!
都是我的错！
It's my fault for being fragile!
都怪我脆弱！
I can't kill enemies on the battlefield!
我无法 在战场上杀死敌人！
Young Master!
少爷！
I was born with a weak constitution!
我生来 体质就弱！
All because of me!
都是因为我！
♪ Farewell words have not left my lips ♪
♪ 告别之言 尚未离开我的嘴 ♪
Shu,
舒，
I beg you.
我求求你。
Can you kill me please?
你能杀了我吗？
Just kill me.
杀了我吧。
A shadow abandoned by its master
被主人遗弃的影子
he deserves to die.
他该死。
I deserve to die.
我该死。
There is a way to maintain life.
有一种方法可以维持生命。
Rumor says that
有传言说
que la medicina divina en Jieshuo
que la medicina divina en Jieshuo
It can help even the sickest people recover from their illness.
它甚至可以帮助病情最严重的人康复。
young master,
少爷，
We will seek divine medicine together.
我们将一起寻求 神药。
No.
不。
We shouldn't go there.
我们不应该去那里。
The Cui and Jieshuo Army
The Cui and Jieshuo Army
They are sworn enemies.
他们是不共戴天的敌人。
Ying's mother died at the hands of the Jieshuo people.
英的母亲死于 界朔人之手。
I never go to
我从不去
seek their help.
寻求他们的帮助。
♪ Life and death mean nothing ♪
♪ 生与死毫无意义 ♪
Young master,
少爷，
You can only see Lieutenant Him when you are alive.
你只有活着的时候才能见到他中尉。
And hope she changes her mind when you're alive.
并希望当你还活着时她会改变主意。
♪ Wait by your side ♪
♪ 在你身边等着 ♪
If you take divine medicine and recover from your condition,
如果吃了神药 ，病情痊愈了，
maybe the lieutenant
也许是中尉
will be able to see by then, Li Ni's true colors
到时候就能看清 李妮的真面目了
Maybe Lieutenant He will be able to see how sincere you were towards her.
也许何中尉能 看出你对她有多真诚。
By then she will change her mind.
到时候她就会改变主意。
Ella...
艾拉……
You're right.
你说得对。
♪ If only I could appreciate this momentary warmth ♪
♪ 如果我能体会 这短暂的温暖就好了 ♪
I have to stay alive.
我必须活下去。
♪ If only I could live this moment for you ♪
♪ 如果我能 为你活这一刻就好了 ♪
I can only see Ying when I'm alive.
我只有活着的时候才能见到莹。
I can only protect her when she is alive.
我只能在她还活着的时候保护她。
If one day,
如果有一天，
I become healthy
我变得健康
and I am able to kill enemies on the battlefield,
我能够 在战场上杀死敌人，
She will fall for me by then.
到时候她就会爱上我的。
Then,
然后，
will stop falling for Li Ni.
将不再爱上李妮。
ying will definitely fall for me.
莹一定会爱上我的。
And!
和！
Yeah.
是的。
By then,
到时，
You will definitely fall for me.
你一定会爱上我的。
The weather is cold tonight.
今晚天气很冷。
You should rest inside.
你应该在里面休息。
At that time,
当时，
I thought no one could rival me.
我以为没有人能与我竞争。
Pei Xian was getting old
裴贤已经老了
while Cui Yi was being held by Jieshuo.
while Cui Yi was being held by Jieshuo.
But now,
但现在，
Looks like I made the wrong move.
看来我的举动是错误的。
Ya que Cui Yi ha reclamado a Dongdu
Ya que Cui Yi ha reclamado a Dongdu
He and Li Ni are surely involved in a conflict.
他和李妮肯定 是有矛盾的。
If he kills Lord Liang, the false emperor,
如果他杀了梁王 这个假皇帝，
it will be
这将是
Li Ni's sworn enemy by then.
那时李妮的死敌。
Even if they come to me together,
即使他们一起来找我，
we can have a show
我们可以表演
and see who has the last laugh.
看看谁能笑到最后。
I told him.
我告诉他了。
Lord Xin cannot defend a city
辛君不能守城
with its capacity.
以其能力。
Luckily, we would escape quickly.
幸好我们逃得快。
But,
但，
once uncle conquered Luoyang City,
一旦叔叔攻克洛阳城，
Who knows what will happen to us by then?
谁知道到那时我们会发生什么？
Now that guy
现在那个家伙
He has lost his son,
他失去了儿子，
I'm sure he's furious.
我确信他很生气。
He won't have time to take care of me.
他不会有时间照顾我。
But this way,
但这样一来，
I am the only person
我是唯一的人
who can inherit the assets of the Cui family.
谁能继承崔氏家族的财产。
After all he is my uncle.
毕竟他是我叔叔。
What if the Great General finds out that Young Master Cui was assaulted...
万一大将军知道 崔公子被人袭击了怎么办……
It is impossible.
是不可能的。
All our men dressed up.
我们所有的男人都盛装打扮。
Even if you investigate the case,
就算你调查了这个案子，
can only find out
只能找出
which were Li Jun's men.
都是李俊的手下。
But,
但，
how could he attack Luoyang City
他怎么能攻打洛阳城呢？
out of spite?
出于怨恨？
If the Grand General interrogates Lord Xin,
若大将军审问辛君，
I'm afraid Lord Xin will...
恐怕辛王爷会……
Even if he did extract information from it,
即使他确实 从中提取了信息，
even if Li Jun revealed all the details,
即使李俊透露了所有细节，
I would just take his mouth off.
我只想把他的嘴摘下来。
I would be spilling nonsense.
我会胡言乱语。
Think about it.
想一想。
Not just Li Jun puso
不只是李俊puso
and kill his son,
并杀了他的儿子，
but it also drove a wedge between my uncle and me.
但这也使 我和叔叔之间产生了隔阂。
Why would the uncle trust him?
为什么叔叔会信任他？
You have served me for so long.
你已经服侍我 这么久了。
Can you use your brain for once?
你能用一下脑子吗？
Yes sir.
是的先生。
If yes, should we hide
如果是的话，我们应该隐藏吗
somewhere and see how the situation works?
某处看看情况如何？
That's the only thing we can do.
这是我们唯一能做的。
Master, it's...
师父，这是...
That's all we have!
那是我们所有的东西！
Do you still want to eat?
你还想吃吗？
What a glutton.
真是个贪吃的人啊。
Lieutenant,
中尉，
Lord Qin sent us a letter.
秦王给我们送了一封信。
He also had something good for you.
他也有一些好东西给你。
Here you have.
在这里你有。
(The war is near.)
（战争临近了。）
(I suddenly remember that you loved this.)
（我突然想起来 你很喜欢这个。）
(I have sent you this to relieve your boredom.)
（我给你发这个 是为了解解你的无聊。）
(As the saying goes, chew delicately like crushed jade,)
（俗话说，细嚼慢咽 ，如碎玉石）
(And take advantage of the momentum like cutting bamboo.)
（并利用 如砍竹子之势。）
(I hope to crush the enemy's morale.)
（我希望能挫伤敌人的士气。）
(I wish you success, and you can achieve victory.)
（祝你成功， 你能取得胜利。）
(After returning to the capital,)
（回到首都后）
(I'm willing to go for dried fruit)
（我愿意去吃 干果）
(And enjoy the nuts there in abundance.)
（并享受那里丰富的坚果。）
(I will trust both flanks and my rear wing)
（我会信任两侧 和我的后翼）
(and you.)
（你呢。）
(Send my gaze to Great General Cui.)
（将目光投向崔大将军。）
Lieutenant,
中尉，
What did Lord Qin write in his letter?
秦王的信里写了什么？
Wait to
等着
that we can achieve victory.
我们能够取得胜利。
So, he sent all this here
所以，他把这些都发到这里了
as a sign of good luck?
作为好运的标志？
It's true.
这是真的。
Disturbed Ear to deliver these nuts all the way here
不安的耳朵把这些坚果一路送到这里
to wish us luck.
祝我们好运。
He delivers the nuts here
他把坚果送到这里
It has nothing to do with me.
这与我无关。
You're being stubborn when you haven't had these nuts, huh?
当你没有 这些坚果的时候你就太固执了，是吧？
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Eat it.
吃了它。
Youde.
Youde.
What's happening?
发生了什么？
Mr. Shiqi, I can't accept it anymore!
十七先生，我不能接受了！
The Cui Army sold Tong Pass out of
崔军出卖潼关
and caused the death of many brothers!
还造成了很多兄弟的死亡！
As we can
尽我们所能
form an alliance and attack Xichang together with them?
结盟 ，与他们一起攻打西昌？
What if they betray us again?
如果他们再次背叛我们怎么办？
What should we do by then?
到时候我们该怎么办呢？
That's right!
这是正确的！
What if
如果什么
they betray us
他们背叛了我们
and they surround us from behind?
他们从后面包围我们？
I met Cui Yi before.
我以前见过崔毅。
It will not.
它不会。
As a father, as a son.
作为父亲，作为儿子。
If your son did that,
如果你儿子这么做了
I'm sure his father would too!
我相信他的父亲也会如此！
If Cui Yi was someone like that,
如果崔毅是这样的人的话
He wouldn't let me leave Luoyang.
他不让我离开洛阳。
He wouldn't let me bring the Father back here.
他不让我 把天父带回来。
Señor Shiqi,
Señor Shiqi,
You are sure that
你确定
Can we still trust the Cui Army?
我们还能相信崔军吗？
The Zhenxi Army has entrusted its flanks and rear wing
镇西军已将 侧翼和后翼托付
us?
我们？
It's because our army is stronger than yours.
因为我们的军队 比你们的军队强。
That's why they trusted their flanks
这就是为什么他们信任自己的侧翼
and rear wing to us.
和我们的后翼。
Li Ni is bold indeed.
李妮确实大胆。
I don't fear him
我不怕他
that could cut your retirement
这可能会减少你的退休生活
and they caught him in Xichang, huh?
他们在西昌抓到了他，是吗？
Father, will you do it?
父亲，你会做吗？
I trust them.
我相信他们。
If Mr. Shiqi trusts them,
如果世奇先生信任他们的话，
I will trust them too.
我也会相信他们。
I trust them too.
我也信任他们。
Mr. Shiqi, I trust you.
Mr. Shiqi, I trust you.
Yes that's how it is,
是的，就是这样，
I will also trust Mr. Shiqi.
我也会相信世奇先生。
you,
你，
do you trust me?
你信任我吗？
Of course I trust you.
我当然相信你。
Thanks for trusting me.
感谢您对我的信任。
Ven.
文。
Once we claim Xichang,
一旦我们占领了西昌，
Let's roast a whole lamb together.
我们一起烤一整只羊吧。
Forget the sheep.
忘记那只羊吧。
We have to have liquid.
我们必须有液体。
It's true. We need to have liquor.
这是真的。我们需要有酒。
Greetings.
问候。
- Come on. - Greetings!
- 快点。 - 问候！
I would have tried it a long time ago
我很久以前就尝试过
if it were not for you.
如果不是为了你。
Padre,
神父，
you would not do that.
你不会那样做的。
Nevertheless,
尽管如此，
even if the Cui Army
即使崔军
and the Zhenxi Army
还有镇西军
have more soldiers than Sun Jing's garrison,
兵力比 孙敬的驻军还多，
it is easy to defend Xichang
守西昌易如反掌
It is difficult to attack.
很难攻击。
Although Li Ni is anathema,
虽然李妮是令人厌恶的，
He doesn't seem like a reckless person.
他看起来不像是一个鲁莽的人。
Have you made other arrangements
你有没有做出其他安排
in the city?
在城市？
So Father, you found out.
所以父亲，你发现了。
Actually, Li Ni already sent his men into the city
其实李尼已经派人进城了
and secretly spread rumors a few days ago
并于前几天偷偷散布谣言
to make people panic
使人们恐慌
and compete for food.
并争夺食物。
Now, people are panicking.
现在，人们陷入恐慌。
Once we attack the city,
一旦我们进攻这座城市
the city
城市
will fall into chaos.
将会陷入混乱。
and I predict
我预测
that will burn down the barn
这会烧毁谷仓
or steal food.
或偷食物。
Once the city is in chaos and there is no food in the granary,
一旦城市乱了 ，粮仓里没有粮食了，
The soldiers guarding the city will die of hunger.
守城的士兵 都会饿死。
This way, attacking the city will be much easier.
这样一来，攻城的话 就会容易很多。
Really?
真的吗？
What's happening?
发生了什么？
Father, do you think
父亲，你认为
Is that arrangement inappropriate?
这样的安排不合适吗？
Li Ni may look young, but he is mature.
李妮虽然看起来年轻，但他却很成熟。
You probably have one more ace up your sleeve.
你可能还有一张王牌 。
And, it's likely that your plan will be the nail in the coffin.
而且，你的计划很可能 会成为棺材上的钉子。
Burning down the barn
烧毁谷仓
and disturb the peace of the people
扰乱人民安宁
They are not good enough.
他们还不够好。
Actually, I also predict
其实我也预测
who has another ace up his sleeve.
谁还有另一张王牌。
Nevertheless,
尽管如此，
I can not tell
我不能说
what's on your mind for now.
你现在在想什么。
Now, I feel like I understand
现在我感觉我明白了
because
因为
you fell next to him.
你倒在他身边。
Padre,
神父，
We are talking about official business here.
我们在这里谈论的是 公事。
He was not as bold and meticulous as him
他没有他那么大胆和细致
when I was your age
当我像你这么大的时候
even though I compromised Jieshuo
即使我妥协了杰硕
in numerous battles
在无数场战斗中
back then.
那时。
Father, how could I compare you?
爸爸，我怎么能和你相比呢？
Era
时代
just luck.
只是运气而已。
He was not proud or arrogant even though he was from the imperial family.
虽是皇室出身，但他并不骄傲，也不傲慢。
Participated in several battles from Laolan Pass
参加 老兰关多次战斗
so far.
迄今为止。
He intends to reclaim his lost empire,
他要夺回失去的帝国，
and is protected by a large army.
并且有庞大的军队保护。
Is more than
超过
just luck.
只是运气而已。
Father, you are praising him too much.
爸爸，您太夸奖他了。
I think that
我觉得
does not deserve
不值得
He deserves all those praises.
他值得所有这些赞扬。
Since they praised him
既然大家都夸他
for my daughter,
为了我的女儿，
naturally,
自然，
He also deserves my praise.
他也值得我称赞。
If so, father, will you stop hitting him in the future?
如果是这样，爸爸，您以后就别再打他了吗？
I said that
我说了
He was good at war.
他擅长战争。
But when it comes to marrying my daughter,
但到了 娶女儿的时候
You can dream about it.
你可以梦想一下。
You're saying it again.
你又说起来了
Lord Qin is going to attack the city soon.
秦王 马上就要攻城了。
¿ No dijeron al General Pingliang, cui Yi,
¿ No dijeron al General Pingliang, cui Yi,
conquer Dongdu?
conquer Dongdu?
That is Lord Qin's strength.
这就是秦王的实力。
No just god to Cui Yi a generous don,
不只是上天给了崔屹 一个慷慨的唐，
que era Dongdu,
que era Dongdu,
but also convinced
但也深信不疑
the Cui army to join him
崔军归附
in conquering Xichang.
in conquering Xichang.
Padre,
神父，
say: “Do you think Lord Qin will achieve success?
说道：“你认为秦王 会成功吗？
On the surface, it seems that he is going to attack Xichang
从表面上看，他似乎是要 攻打西昌。
along with the Cui Army.
与崔军一起。
However, I'm sure it did
不过，我确信它做到了
other secret plans.
其他秘密计划。
I just don't know
我只是不知道
what are your plans
你的计划是什么
and how to support it.
以及如何支持它。
Prime Minister!
总理！
We are in trouble!
我们有麻烦了！
Has Lord Qin attacked the city?
秦王攻城了吗？
Some troublemakers have broken into the barn.
一些捣乱分子闯入了谷仓。
They robbed the barn!
他们抢劫了谷仓！
The guards there
那里的守卫
They couldn't stop them.
他们无法阻止他们。
After that, for some reason,
之后，由于某种原因，
The barn caught fire.
谷仓着火了。
It was raided and burned.
它遭到袭击并被烧毁。
I fear that
我担心
there's not much left.
所剩无几了。
Very good. I understand.
非常好。我明白。
You can go.
你可以走了。
Order our men to guard the door.
命令我们的人看守大门。
Yeah.
是的。
Wan'niang,
Wan'niang,
now you understand?
你现在明白了？
So, he was targeting the city with his plans.
所以，他的计划就是针对这座城市的。
It's true.
这是真的。
First, he spread rumors of
首先，他散布谣言
the lack of food in the city.
城市里缺乏食物。
It caused panic among the people.
引起了民众的恐慌。
After that, he instigated the rioters
此后，他煽动暴徒
rob and burn the barn.
抢劫并烧毁谷仓。
Now,
现在，
there is no food in the city.
城里没有食物。
The soldiers guarding the city will have to starve.
守城的士兵 将不得不挨饿。
I'm sure they're in no mood to defend the city.
我确信他们没有心情 保卫这座城市。
It's true.
这是真的。
Now, Lord Liang has proclaimed himself emperor.
如今，梁王已经称帝了 。
Sun Jing was known as a tyrant.
孙敬被称为暴君。
And, the city is in chaos.
而且，这座城市一片混乱。
Xichang
西昌
will fall.
会摔倒。
Your Highness!
殿下！
The rioters have robbed the barn.
暴徒抢劫了谷仓。
I fear that Li Ni: attack the city soon.
我担心李妮： 攻城不久。
Jing,
静,
I don't want you to go to war anymore.
我不想再让你去打仗了
Let's go.
我们走吧。
I thought
我想
time flew
时间飞逝
since we met.
自从我们相遇以来。
We have already lived half our lives in the blink of an eye.
转眼间我们已经走过了一半的人生。
Why not
为什么不
put on a suit of armor
穿上铠甲
and join you in the defense of the city?
并与你一起保卫城市？
Don't say such ridiculous things.
别说这么可笑的话。
Stay here.
待在这。
I will drink with you again
我会再和你一起喝酒
once I close Li Ni.
一旦我关闭了李妮。
I will wait for your return.
我会等你回来。
Wait for my return.
等我回来。
Attack!
攻击！
Charge!
收费！
Here and here.
这里和这里。
Increases defense around those areas.
增加这些区域周围的防御。
Reporting!
报告！
Great governor,
伟大的州长，
the Zhenxi army and the Cui army are too ruthless.
镇西军和崔军 太狠了。
They have put in stepped stairs.
他们安装了阶梯式楼梯。
Several of our doors are under assault.
我们的几扇门 受到攻击。
Our forces are exhausted.
我们的力量已经耗尽。
We are suffering many casualties!
我们伤亡惨重！
Order the Imperial Army rear detachment to scale the city wall.
命令皇军后 支队攀登城墙。
(Sun) Guard the doors.
（太阳） 守门。
No one is allowed to withdraw!
任何人都不得退出！
Those who go against my order will be executed!
违抗我命令者， 一律处死！
Yes, Great Governor!
是的，伟大的总督！
Great governor,
伟大的州长，
The rioters have started fighting our soldiers.
暴乱者开始 与我们的士兵作战。
Some are even stealing the kerosene that defends the doors!
有些人甚至偷了 守门的煤油！
Mr. Governor, please give us your instruction!
请州长先生赐教 ！
Don't leave any of
不要留下任何一个
the rioters alive.
暴徒还活着。
Kill everyone.
把所有人干掉。
Yes, Great Governor.
是的，伟大的总督。
Mr. Governor, the city is in chaos.
州长先生，这座城市一片混乱。
We are in a difficult situation.
我们的处境很困难。
Great governor, why don't you get out of town
伟大的州长，你为什么不出 城呢？
and regroup our forces at Tong Pass?
并在潼关集结部队？
We just have to endure their attack for a few more days.
我们只需要再忍受 他们的攻击几天就可以了。
By then, the army I have sent to Baiyue will return.
到时候，我派往百越的军队 就会回来了。
Naturally, we will be able to surround the Zhenxi Army and the Cui Army
自然能够包围 镇西军和崔军
and they annihilate them.
他们消灭了他们。
Great governor,
伟大的州长，
When there is life, there is hope!
有生命就有希望！
¡Deja!
德哈！
Order all soldiers to
命令所有士兵
Great Governor!
伟大的州长！
- Great Governor!
- 伟大的州长！
(Zhenxi)
(Zhenxi)
Your Majesty!
陛下！
The Zhenxi Army has entered the city!
镇西军已经进城了！
(Mrs. Jin,)
（金女士）
(Since I have agreed to launch a double attack with Li Ni,)
（既然我已经答应和李妮发起 双重攻击了，）
(we have to deliver the fatal blow)
（我们必须给予致命一击）
(to Sun Jing also inside the palace.)
（对也在宫内的孙敬说。）
Your Highness, please wake up!
殿下，请醒醒吧！
¡Alú!
¡阿鲁！
♪ If I forget the fleeting nature of time ♪
♪ 如果我忘记了时间的短暂 ♪
♪ Wait for the memories ♪
♪ 等待回忆 ♪
♪ smash and sink ♪
♪ 粉碎并沉没 ♪
♪ The emotional scars on your heart ♪
♪ 你心中的情感伤痕 ♪
♪ They are the mess ♪
♪ 他们真是一团糟 ♪
♪ I find it difficult to let go ♪
♪ 我发现很难放手 ♪
♪ If the longing is not forgotten ♪
♪ 如果没有忘记渴望 ♪
♪ I long to return to the first moment ♪
♪ 渴望回到 最初的时刻 ♪
♪ The affection we had in our fateful situation ♪
♪ 我们在命运的处境中所拥有的感情♪
♪ How I wish to keep it for you ♪
♪ 我多么想为你保留它 ♪
♪ If you still remember love ♪
♪ 如果你还记得爱情 ♪
♪ The promises we made ♪
♪ 我们许下的承诺 ♪
♪ Even if this love hurts me ♪
♪ 即使这份爱让我受伤 ♪
♪ I will continue living for you ♪
♪ 我会继续为你而活 ♪
♪ holding on to memories ♪
♪ 紧紧抓住回忆 ♪
♪ Wait it's my persistence ♪
♪ 等等，这是我的坚持 ♪
♪ If love remembers ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪ 尽管违背命运 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪ 我愿意牺牲你 ♪
♪ While waiting for your response ♪
♪ 在等待您的回复时 ♪
♪ If love is remembered ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪ 尽管违背命运 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪ 我愿意牺牲你 ♪
♪ While I wait for your response ♪
♪ 在等待你的回复时 ♪